David White-Goode | Software Engineer

Brooklyn, NY 646.709.3405 <u>dwhitegoode@gmail.com</u> LinkedIn Github Portfolio

Technical Skills

IT professional of two years and a Software Engineer early in his career with a background of building dynamic web applications in React. Looking to join a great team of developers and contribute towards delivering meaningful applications to users.

Experienced in - ReactJS, JavaScript, HTML/CSS,, NodeJS, MongoDB, SQL, Git

Technical Projects

Hater App - Deployed | React | Django | PostgreSQL

- A social media app built with Django and React on a PostgreSQL database in which users can create as well as comment on each other's posts.
- Built with robust RESTful API routes with token authentication.

The Inner Bod - <u>Deployed</u> | React | MongoDB | Node | Express

- A website built in React, Node, and Express on a MongoDB database that serves users with health information based on input.
- Worked within a scrum team to develop solutions to users' health inquiries incorporating regular standups, sprints, and task estimations.
- Built a REST API using Express and Mongoose deployed with Heroku.

Experience

Software Engineering Fellow | New York, NY

General Assembly

Feb 2022 – May 2022

- 12 weeks of rigorous project-based learning focused on full stack React development.
- Built and managed rich frontend components in solo and group projects.
- Designed and implemented backend API endpoints.
- Used Agile practices for a modern workflow in team projects.

Data Analyst | Rosemead, CA

Infosys Ltd

May 2019 – Mar 2020

- Loaded and transformed large sets of structured, semi-structured and unstructured data with Apache Hadoop.
- Analyzed the data by performing Hive queries.
- Monitored Apache Hadoop jobs processing ETL tasks, starting and restarting scripts or resolving errors reported through our ticketing system.

Education

General Assembly | New York, NY Certificate Software Engineering Immersive

Feb 2022 – May 2022

CUNY New York City College of Technology | Brooklyn, NY

Jan 2016 - Dec 2018

Bachelor of Technology in Computer Systems